A Finding Aid to the Eric Gugler Papers, 1889-1977, in the Archives of American Art AAA.gugleric
Archives of American Art
- Project Files, 1889-1977; Series 4; 28.2 Linear feet Boxes 5-18, 20-24, OV 25-31, OV 33-49, RD 50-69
  - Buildings, Residential, 1937-1973; 4.3
    - Cornell, Katherine, House, 1950-1971 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
      Oversize material housed in OV 40 and RD 53.
    - Cowles, Russell, House, circa 1941 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      Oversize material housed in Box 23, Folder 2 and OV 40.
    - Faulkner, Barry, House, circa 1937 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Oversize material housed in OV 41 and RD 54.
    - Ford, Mr. and Mrs. Henry, House, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 10-13)
      Oversize material housed in OV 41.
    - Gay, S.B., House, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Gugler, Eric, House, circa 1940-1970 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Gugler, Eric, Sneden's Landing House, 1949-1973 (Box 10, Folder 16-23)
      Oversize material housed in Box 23, Folder 3 and OV 42.
    - Gugler, Ralph, House, circa 1950-1970 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Haagensen, Alice M., House, circa 1945-1970 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Hanes, John, House, circa 1950-1970 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Harris, Mr. and Mrs. Lowell, House, 1966-1969 (Box 10, Folder 27-28)
    - Hendrick, James P., House, circa 1950-1970 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Jackson, James A., Apartment, circa 1945-1970 (Box 10, Folder 30)
      Oversize material housed in OV 42.
    - James, Alexander, Studio, circa 1951-1973 (Box 10, Folder 31)
      Oversize material housed in RD 55.
    - Kearney, Gene R., House, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Kuper, J.B. Horner, House, 1961 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Leavitt, Kent and Molly, House, 1936-1970 (Box 10, Folder 34-37)
      Oversize material housed in OV 42 and RD 56.
    - Macy, Gertrude, House, 1946-1955 (Box 10, Folder 38-41)
    - Manship, Paul, House, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Oversize material housed in Box 23, Folder 4 and OV 42,
    - Mygatt, Mr. and Mrs. Royal E., House, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Nuhn, Mr., House, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Phipps, Mr. and Mrs. Michael, House, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Putnam, David, Monadnock Pavillion, 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Oversize material housed in OV 28.
    - Trudeau, Dr. and Mrs. F.B., House, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Whitney, John Hay, House, circa 1956 (Box 11, Folder 7-8)
    - Unidentified Project, Italy, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified Projects, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Renderings, models, and photographs. Oversize material housed in Box 23, Folder 5 and OV 42.
    - Unidentified Projects, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 11-13)
    - Oversized Coe House Designs from Box 10, Folder 5, circa 1950-1970 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Oversized Cornell House Plans from Box 10, Folder 6, circa 1950-1969 (Box OV 40)
    - Oversized Cornell House Plans from Box 10, Folder 6, circa 1950-1969 (Box RD 53)
    - Oversized Cowles House Plans from Box 10, Folder 8, circa 1941 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Oversized Cowles House Plans from Box 10, Folder 8, circa 1941 (Box OV 40)
    - Oversized Faulkner House Plans from Box 10, Folder 9, circa 1937 (Box OV 41)
    - Oversized Faulkner House Plans from Box 10, Folder 9, circa 1937 (Box RD 54)
    - Oversized Ford House Plans from Box 10, Folder 13, 1957 (Box OV 41)
    - Oversized Gay House Plans from Box 10, Folder 14, 1940 (Box OV 41)
    - Oversized Gugler Sneden's House Plans from Box 10, Folder 22, circa 1953-1970 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Oversized Gugler Sneden's House Plans from Box 10, Folder 22, circa 1953-1970 (Box OV 42)
    - Oversized Jackson Apartment Plans from Box 10, Folder 30, circa 1945-1970 (Box OV 42)
    - Oversized James Studio Plans from Box 10, Folder 31, circa 1951-1973 (Box RD 55)
    - Oversized Leavitt House Plans from Box 10, Folder 34-35, 1936-1970 (Box OV 42)
    - Oversized Leavitt House Plans from Box 10, Folder 34, 1936-1970 (Box RD 56)
    - Oversized Manship House Plans from Box 11, Folder 1, circa 1950-1970 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Oversized Manship House Plans from Box 11, Folder 1, circa 1950-1970 (Box OV 42)
    - Oversized Putnam Pavillion Plans from Box 11, Folder 5, 1967-1968 (Box OV 28)
    - Oversized Unidentified Project Plans from Box 11, Folder 10, circa 1950-1970 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Oversized Unidentified Project Plans from Box 11, Folder 10, circa 1950-1970 (Box OV 42)
  - Design Objects, 1937-1972; 4.4
    - Commercial, Cosmopolitan Club Plaque, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 14)
      Oversize material housed in OV 43.
    - Commercial, Glass Celestial Sphere, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Commercial, Inscription, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Commercial, Medallions, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Commercial, Scroll Designs, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 18)
      Oversize material housed in RD 57-58.
    - Commercial, St. James Church, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Commercial, World's Fair Model, circa 1939 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Patent, Sedan Chair, 1954-1966 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Patent, Single Unit Bathroom, 1938-1972 (Box 11, Folder 22-23)
    - Patent, Sleeping Car, circa 1940-1970 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Residential, Chrystie, Mr. and Mrs. Thomas, Mantle Ornament, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Residential, Newell, Stair Railing, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Residential, Palmer, Charles F., Inscription, 1966-1969 (Box 11, Folder 27-28)
    - Residential, Palmer, Charles F., Sundial, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Residential, Roundy, Mr., Cornice, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Residential, Furniture, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Unidentified Projects, circa 1950-1970 (Box 11, Folder 32-33)
    - Oversized Cosmopolitan Club Plaque from Box 11, Folder 14, circa 1950-1970 (Box OV 43)
    - Oversized Scroll Designs from Box 11, Folder 18, circa 1950-1970 (Box RD 57-58)
    - Oversized Newell Railing Designs from Box 11, Folder 26, circa 1950-1970 (Box OV 43)
    - Oversized Palmer Inscription Designs from Box 11, Folder 28, 1966-1969 (Box OV 43)
    - Oversized Furniture Designs from Box 11, Folder 31, circa 1950-1970 (Box OV 43)
  - Memorials, 1929-1977; 4.5
    - Anzio Cemetery/Sicily-Rome American Cemetery and Memorial, 1947-1973 (Box 11, Folder 34-38)
    - Anzio Cemetery/Sicily-Rome American Cemetery and Memorial, 1949-1977 (Box 11, Folder 39-43)
      Correspondence on design objects and postcards; specifications; and clippings. Oversize material housed in OV 44-46.
    - Anzio Cemetery/Sicily-Rome American Cemetery and Memorial, circa 1950-1960 (Box 11, Folder 44-46)
      Renderings/models. Oversize renderings housed in OV 29 and OV 44-46. Oversize renderings and models housed in Box 23, Folder 6.
    - Anzio Cemetery/Sicily-Rome American Cemetery and Memorial, circa 1947-1957 (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
      Photographs, construction.
    - Anzio Cemetery/Sicily-Rome American Cemetery and Memorial, circa 1952-1960 (Box 12, Folder 6-10)
      Photographs/display. Oversize material housed in OV 29.
    - Battery Park, Bridge, New York City, 1934-1972 (Box 12, Folder 11-18)
    - Battery Park, War Memorial, New York City, 1930-1941 (Box 12, Folder 19-22)
    - Battery Park, War Memorial, New York City, 1929-1933 (Box 12, Folder 23-27)
      Diary, estimates, specifications, writings, and printed material.
    - Battery Park, War Memorial, New York City, circa 1930-1950 (Box 12, Folder 28-31)
      Renderings and photographs/display. Oversize materials housed in Box 23, Folder 7 and OV 47.
    - Corregidor-Bataan Memorial, 1956-1967 (Box 12, Folder 32-36)
      Oversize material housed in Box 23, Folder 8.
    - Edison, Thomas, Memorial, circa 1950-1970 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Ellis Island, War Memorial, New York, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 38)
      Oversize material housed in Box 23, Folder 9 and OV 47.
    - Firestone, Harvey, Memorial, Liberia, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 39)
      Oversize material housed in Box 23, Folder 10, OV 47 and RD 59.
    - Firestone, Harvey, Memorial, Ohio, circa 1949-1960 (Box 12, Folder 40-41)
    - Firestone, Harvey, Memorial, 1970-1972 (Box 12, Folder 42)
      Stetson University proposal.
    - Grange, Hamilton, National Memorial, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Hutchins, Waldo, Memorial, 1929-1968 (Box 13, Folder 2-5)
    - Massee, May, Memorial, 1933-1972 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
      Oversize material housed in OV 47.
    - Mayo, Charles and William, Memorial, circa 1950 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Newark Building Competition, Memorial, circa 1950-1970 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Patton, George, Memorial, circa 1950-1970 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, Memorial, 1962-1966 (Box 13, Folder 11-16)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, Memorial, 1963-1972 (Box 13, Folder 17-21)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, Memorial, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 22-24)
      Estimates, bonds, and specifications.
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, Memorial, circa 1960-1970 (Box 13, Folder 25-28)
      Transmittals, writings, dedication remarks, and printed material.
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, Memorial, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 29-31)
      Renderings and photographs/display. Oversize renderings in RD 60. Oversize photograph in Box 23, Folder 11.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1959-1965 (Box 13, Folder 32-36)
      Correspondence. Oversize material housed in Box 24, Folder 1
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1962-1968 (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1965-1969 (Box 14, Folder 7-10)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1970-1974 (Box 14, Folder 11-15)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, circa 1964-1969 (Box 14, Folder 16-19)
      Correspondence (duplicates).
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1960-1974 (Box 14, Folder 20-22)
      Writings and printed material.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 23-25)
      Early renderings.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 26-27)
      Plaque and sculpture.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 28)
      Tidal basin correspondence.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1966-1972 (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
      Tidal Basin correspondence.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Tidal Basin specifications.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1964-1969 (Box 15, Folder 5-7)
      Tidal Basin renderings. Oversize material housed in Box 24, Folder 1-4 and OV 48-49.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, 1964-1969 (Box 15, Folder 8-10)
      Tidal Basin models, sculpture, and display. Oversize material housed in OV 30.
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, Memorial, circa 1960-1970 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      Warm Springs Foundation negatives.
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, Memorial, 1948-1960 (Box 15, Folder 12-17)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, Memorial, 1961-1963 (Box 15, Folder 18-23)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, Memorial, 1962-1964 (Box 15, Folder 24-26)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, Memorial, 1962-1969 (Box 16, Folder 1-5)
      Correspondence; includes letters regarding inscriptions. Oversize material housed in RD 63-66.
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, Memorial, 1958-1972 (Box 16, Folder 6-8)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, Memorial, circa 1960-1970 (Box 16, Folder 9-14)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, Memorial, 1958-1970 (Box 16, Folder 15-18)
      Bills, estimates, specifications, and writings.
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, Memorial, 1956-1967 (Box 16, Folder 19-20)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, Memorial, 1959-1970 (Box 16, Folder 21-23)
      Renderings. Oversize material housed in Box 24, Folder 5-6, RD 61-62, and RD 67.
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, Memorial, 1960-1970 (Box 16, Folder 24-28)
      Models, fountain, sculpture, dedication, and display. Oversize material housed in Box 24, Folder 5-6.
    - Thayer, Abbott, Memorial, 1944-1948 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Wilson, Woodrow, Memorial, 1944-1946 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - World War I Memorial, Chicago, Illinois, circa 1929-1937 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - World War I Memorial, New York State, 1930-1936 (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
    - War Memorial, Studies, circa 1950-1970 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified Projects, circa 1950-1970 (Box 17, Folder 7-9)
    - Oversized Anzio Cemetery Renderings from Box 11, Folder 40 and 44-45, 1950-1960 (Box OV 44-46)
    - Oversized Anzio Cemetery Renderings and Models from Box 11, Folder 44 and 46, circa 1950-1960 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Oversized Anzio Cemetery Renderings from Box 11, Folder 44, circa 1950-1957 (Box OV 29)
    - Oversized Anzio Cemetery Photographs from Box 12, Folder 6, 1956-1957 (Box OV 29)
    - Oversize Battery Park Renderings from Box 12, Folder 28, circa 1930-1950 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Oversize Battery Park Renderings from Box 12, Folder 28, circa 1930-1950 (Box OV 47)
    - Oversized Corregidor-Bataan Renderings from Box 12, Folder 35, circa 1956-1960 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Oversized Ellis Island Design from Box 12, Folder 38, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Oversized Ellis Island Design from Box 12, Folder 38, 1970 (Box OV 47)
    - Oversized Firestone Renderings from Box 12, Folder 39 and 41, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Oversized Firestone Renderings from Box 12, Folder 39 and 41, 1952 (Box OV 47)
    - Oversized Firestone Renderings from Box 12, Folder 39 and 41, 1952 (Box RD 59)
    - Oversized Massee Plans from Box 13, Folder 6, 1933-1939 (Box OV 47)
    - Oversized E. Roosevelt Renderings from Box 13, Folder 29, 1963-1966 (Box RD 60)
    - Oversized E. Roosevelt Photograph from Box 13, Folder 30, circa 1963-1966 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Oversized F.D. Roosevelt Renderings from Box 13, Folder 34, 1964 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Oversized F.D. Roosevelt Renderings from Box 15, Folder 5-6, circa 1960-1970 (Box 24, Folder 1-4)
    - Oversized F.D. Roosevelt Renderings from Box 15, Folder 6, circa 1960-1970 (Box OV 48-49)
    - Oversized F.D. Roosevelt Photographs from Box 15, Folder 8, 1964-1969 (Box OV 30)
    - Oversized T. Roosevelt Inscription Renderings from Box 16, Folder 1, 1962-1964 (Box RD 63-66)
    - Oversized T. Roosevelt Renderings from Box 16, Folder 21 and 23, 1960-1970 (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
    - Oversized T. Roosevelt Renderings from Box 16, Folder 23, 1960-1970 (Box RD 61-62, 67)
    - Oversized T. Roosevelt Renderings from Box 16, Folder 25, 1960-1970 (Box 24, Folder 5-6)
  - Preservation, 1889-1973; 4.6
    - General Correspondence, 1944-1948 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Bridge, Hudson Thruway, New York, 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Bridge, Potomac River, Washington, D.C., 1956-1958 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Bryan, William Jennings, Memorial, 1961 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Custom House, Sag Harbor, Long Island, 1945-1948 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Governor Smith house, Wiscasset, Maine, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Harrisville Historic Village, New Jersey, 1969-1972 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Hudson River, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Lane's Cove, Massachusetts, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Louisville Court House, Louisiana, 1945-1969 (Box 17, Folder 19-21)
      Oversize material housed in OV 31.
    - New York City National Shrines, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 22-26)
      Includes information on the American Museum of Immigration, Clinton Castle, Federal Hall, and Grant's Tomb. Oversize material housed in OV 31.
    - Octagon House, Washington, D.C., 1948-1964 (Box 17, Folder 27-31)
    - Octagon House, Washington, D.C., 1965-1969 (Box 17, Folder 32-36)
      Correspondence; includes letters regarding the stable.
    - Octagon House, Washington, D.C., 1965-1973 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
      Correspondence; includes letters regarding the stable and possible vice president's residence.
    - Octagon House, Washington, D.C., circa 1949-1970 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Octagon House, Washington, D.C., 1953-1962 (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
    - Octagon House, Washington, D.C., circa 1955-1965 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Renderings and photographs. Oversize material housed in OV 31.
    - Roads and Highways, 1956-1959 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Saint-Gaudens Memorial, Cornish, New Hampshire, 1946-1969 (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
    - St. Peter's, Rome, Italy, circa 1913-1973 (Box 18, Folder 10-13)
    - St. Peter's, Rome, Italy, 1889-1936 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - St. Peter's, Rome, Italy, 1970-1973 (Box 18, Folder 15-16)
      Photographs/models and display.
    - Washington Square, New York, New York, circa 1960-1970 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Oversized Louisville Court House Renderings from Box 17, Folder 21, 1946-1969 (Box OV 31)
    - Oversized New York City National Shrines Renderings from Box 17, Folder 24, 1950-1952 (Box OV 31)
      Renderings of Clinton Castle.
    - Oversized Octagon House Renderings from Box 18, Folder 6, circa 1955-1965 (Box OV 31)
  - Sculptures, 1930-1971; 4.7
    - Angel Gabriel, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Armillary Spheres, 1968-1971 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Astrological Models, 1930-1934 (Box 18, Folder 20-22)
    - Eagles, circa 1950-1970 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Europa and the Bull, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Lincoln, Abraham, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Nativity Scene, circa 1950-1970 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - Pegasus, 1966-1971 (Box 18, Folder 27)
      Oversized material housed in RD 68-69.
    - Miscellaneous Sculptures, circa 1945-1970 (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Oversized Pegasus Renderings from Box 18, Folder 27, 1966-1971 (Box RD 68-69)
- Personal Business Records, 1928-1972; Series 5; 0.3 Linear feet Box 18
  Personal business records consist of correspondence, invoices, and legal contracts related to Gugler’s firm and his personal accounts. There are also office leases, prospective client lists, and guidelines for service fees.
  - Gugler, Eric, Personal Accounts, 1928-1969 (Box 18, Folder 29-30)
  - Gugler, Cain, and Associates, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Gugler and Kimball, 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Office Leases, 1937-1940 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Prospect File, 1954-1959 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Service Fees, circa 1950-1960 (Box 18, Folder 35-36)
- Printed Material, 1923-1977; Series 6; 0.3 Linear feet Boxes 19, 24
  Printed material includes newspaper and magazine research clippings, postcards, miscellaneous items, and exhibition material for Gugler’s 1977 exhibition in Cornish, New Hampshire.
  - Clippings, Antique Ships, circa 1923-1942 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, Illustrations, circa 1925-1970 (Box 19, Folder 2-3)
  - Clippings, Nimes, France, 1950-1970 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, U.S. History and News, circa 1932-1971 (Box 19, Folder 5-9)
    Oversize material housed in Box 24, Folder 7.
  - Exhibition Material, Cornish, New Hampshire, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Postcards, circa 1940-1970 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1950-1970 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Oversized Clippings from Box 19, Folder 9, 1956-1971 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Photographic Materials, 1890-1966; Series 7; 9 Folders Box 19
  Photographic materials are of Eric Gugler and members of the Gugler family, including Frida, Julius, and Oswald Gugler. The series also includes a photo album of Gugler’s travels in Greece and Italy in 1914.
  Materials are minimally arranged by document type. Photographs and negatives of individual buildings and houses designed by Gugler can be found in project files.
  - Gugler, Eric, circa 1910-1966 (Box 19, Folder 13-15)
  - Gugler, Frida, circa 1895-1966 (Box 19, Folder 16-17)
  - Gugler, Julius, circa 1890-1915 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Gugler, Oswald, circa 1900 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Gugler Family Home, circa 1895-1920 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Photo Album, Greece and Italy, 1914 (Box 19, Folder 21)
- Artwork, 1895-1970; Series 8; 0.4 Linear feet Box 19, OV 32
  Artwork includes graphite and pen and ink sketches, watercolors, paintings, photographs of artwork, and artwork by Gugler's sister, Frida. Gugler’s loose sketches are predominantly figure studies, landscapes, and studies for mural and sculptural designs. The series also includes two sketchbooks that document Gugler's travels in Italy and Spain.
  - Painting, circa 1930-1970 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    Oversize material housed in OV 32.
  - Sketchbook, Italy, circa 1930-1970 (Box 19, Folder 23-24)
  - Sketchbook, Spain, circa 1930-1970 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Sketches, Graphite, circa 1930-1970 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Sketches, Pen and Ink, circa 1930-1970 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Watercolors, circa 1930-1970 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Photographs of Artwork, circa 1950-1970 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - By Frieda Gugler, circa 1895-1965 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Oversized Paintings and Sketches from Box 19, Folder 22 and 26, circa 1930-1970 (Box OV 32)